<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Caliber Contracting</title>
    <description>Caliber Consulting is a web and mobile application consulting company aimed at making your ideas come to life with beautiful and intuitive designs. Our team of developers will work with you to make websites and applications users will come back to again and again.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:52:29 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:52:29 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Caliber Consulting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Caliber Consulting, a collaborative development team composed of talented Computer Science students from the University of Kansas. Working primarily in the Kansas City area, we produce websites and mobile applications for a variety of clientele.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to browse through the site, meet some of our developers, and view a collection of our past work on the portfolio tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in working with us? Hop over to the “Contact Us” tab and pass your contact information along to us. We’ll be in touch soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Evan Nichols&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 02:19:12 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>/first/post/2016/01/04/welcome-to-Caliber-Consulting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/first/post/2016/01/04/welcome-to-Caliber-Consulting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>first</category>
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bridging the Gap</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone is familiar with the age old “I can’t get a job without experience, but I can’t get experience without a job” paradox that plagues so many undergraduate students in engineering and beyond. Attending the Engineering Career Fair my freshman year, I recall vividly a recruiter, after scanning over my resume for a few seconds, handing it back and saying, &lt;em&gt;“I’m sorry but we’re looking for candidates with a little more prior experience.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I didn’t take it personally – one doesn’t expect a successful company to just hand out internships to freshman – it was a bit disheartening as it happened to me over and over again at each booth I visited. I left the career fair with zero next day interviews, and question inkling in my brain: “How do I get experience?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set out to find this magical “experience” that so many recruiters desired to see. My search took my to the Freshman Engineering Student Council. FESC proved to be a great way to meet other engineering students, but I quickly found our responsibilities were limited to creating and hanging posters around the engineering school, and chalking the sidewalks to publicize SoE events. It was a step in the right direction, but not the total solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on as a freshman, I got involved in KU Student Senate. I helped organize the campaign for Marcus Tetwiler’s Ad Astra Coalition. It was quite the ride. The energy that accompanied joining a completely new coalition (with some admittedly lofty platforms) was addicting. I wasn’t just hanging up posters. I was attending coalition meetings, debating what the Senate’s top priorities should be, and presenting at greek houses and scholarship halls urging people to be informed voters for the upcoming election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campaign was a success, yielding the largest voter turnout in the history of Senate Elections, and a landslide victory for the Ad Astra party. I would later serve as an Off-Campus senator for Student Senate for a year, helping a variety of student organizations apply for Senate funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My journey did not stop there. I joined the KU Energy Club as a sophomore, and helped coordinate the 4th Annual KU Energy Conference, a day long event in the spring dedicated to engaging students, teachers and industry professionals in meaningful discussion and debate relevant to the energy industry today (If that sounds like it came straight off a resume, it’s because it did). Just like Ad Astra, it was a fast-moving, high-energy experience that included reaching out to keynote speakers and discussion panelists, designing marketing material, and ultimately, live-tweeting the entire event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was happy. Walking into the career fair as a sophomore, resume teeming with “experience,” I was a page out of Dr. Seuss’s “Oh, the Places You’ll Go.” Ready to move mountains, impress some recruiters, and kick some ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That didn’t happen, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recruiters didn’t hand my resume right back to me this time. In fact, I had great conversations with quite a few of them, discussing my Student Senate and Energy Club experiences. And I even got a two next day interviews! I was ecstatic. One step closer to a real position. But I found myself struggling to answer technical questions. My projects from EECS 268 – Programming II – barely passed as real “projects” (I thought interviewers would be more impressed with my ability to implement a Binary Search Tree, but alas), and I struggled to answer the technical questions they threw at me. After a few days, my inbox pinged with two follow up emails, both bearing statements only slightly different than what I had heard as a freshman at the Career Fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We’re looking for a candidate with experience more related to the position we are seeking to fill.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made sense. And it pained me I had been so naive, thinking coursework alone would suffice as related experience. Sure, my involvement outside of class was a positive indicator of my work ethic, but it wouldn’t cut it. I needed experience related to EECS. But where would I find it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out my first related work experience would come in a phone call from Grant Isom, the co-founder of Caliber. The founder of Passel, a social calendar application, had found Grant online and asked him to develop the mobile and web platforms for the application. With my background in graphic design, Grant asked if I would want to work with him on the UI/UX application. It was the perfect opportunity, and I agreed to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking graphically, the next 6 months were an exponential learning curve. Developing a user interface was accompanied with its fair share of challenges. I had never used Photoshop and Git to manage the designs and image assets for a project, and there were plenty of nights of scouring Stack Overflow in frustration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the work paid off. We completed the iOS and web versions of the application for Passel, marking the first successful project we had completed for a client. The experience was more rewarding than any project or assignment I had completed for school. There was a little more swagger to my step when I walked into the career fair as a junior, ready to shower them with stories of experiences related to the position they were seeking to fill. I walked out of the career fair with three next day interviews, and, a few weeks later, an internship offer from Garmin. I had finally broken the vicious “no work without experience, no experience without work” cycle through a successful freelance job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, enough about me. Actually, way too much about me. Why did I choose to share these all these experiences? Because I’m betting at least a few of you have been in the same position before. Searching for that perfect club or organization that will blow recruiters out of the water. Applying for your dream jobs, but falling short with applicable experiences. That is precisely the problem we are trying to solve with Caliber Contracting. There exists a gap between talented EECS students and companies and clients looking for developers. Students may not have industry contacts to reach out to, or be familiar with the logistics of organizing a job. Caliber is seeking to break down that barrier, connecting students and clients together to create meaningful applications and websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just this week, Grant and Cole met with Tahki Bannister, a professional barber and founder &lt;a href=&quot;http://mycutstravel.com/&quot;&gt;My Cuts Travel&lt;/a&gt;, who is looking to develop a mobile application for customers to record and share their past haircuts. We’re working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://prepskc.com/&quot;&gt;PrepsKC&lt;/a&gt; to improve their live scoring iPad application for high school football programs in Kansas City. Clients and companies see their ideas come to fruition, and students get a chance to contribute to real-life projects. So maybe next time they walk into a career fair or apply to a company, they can point to their client work and say, “I did that.” I’d say that’s about the most relevant work experience you can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that, welcome to Caliber Contracting. We’re excited to bring students and companies together in a meaningful way. We’ll be posting content to this blog regularly as a way to record our experiences along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Evan Nichols&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 05:58:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/company/2015/04/14/bridging-the-gap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/company/2015/04/14/bridging-the-gap.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>company</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
